Here it comes.
要來了
- You mean, Shoji? - He's not here.
如果是捲捲頭的話…
An earthquake.
地震要來了
Don't tell me that you can even predict earthquakes.
就算是你
Here it comes.
真的來了
It's big.
好晃啊
Get under your desks!
請大家躲到桌子底下
Stop working, Omae.
大前小姐，不用管工作了
Hurry.
快點
- Mori! - Watch out!
-森 -危險
Don't move.
別動
Until it stops shaking,
在地震完全停止前
stay under your desks.
請大家不要離開桌子底下
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
Mori?
森？
Yes.
啊…是
I'm fine.
我沒事
Can I talk to Nanako?
奈奈子？叫她跟我說話
Hello? Is this Nana?
奈奈嗎？
It's Dad.
是爸比喔
It was scary, wasn't it?
搖來搖去的很害怕吧
I had no idea he had a kid.
原來近先生有小孩啊
Hey.
姐姐
Are my beetle larvae okay?
獨角仙幼蟲的櫃子 有沒有倒下來？
Hi there, it's me.
喂喂？是我
How's everything? Is everything okay?
怎麼樣？
Your phone is ringing.
你的手機響了
Oh, yeah, sorry.
是，不好意思
Hello? Mum?
喂喂？媽媽？
It was so scary.
我快嚇死了
- Hello? - Ken? Are you all right?
喂喂？小賢，你沒事吧？
It was a big one.
晃得真厲害呢
Yeah. Are you okay, Shoji?
東海林先生你沒事吧
I hate earthquakes. I got so scared.
我最討厭地震，快被嚇死了
By the way, how's Turtleneck?
話說回來，那個套頭毛衣女 怎麼樣？
Was she also scared?
那女人應該也怕地震吧
Well, actually...
不，關於這個…
Not at all.
她完全不怕
She kept on working as usual.
像往常一樣在工作
What?
天啊
I bet she has nobody to call even in times like this.
那種傢伙在這種時候 果然連打電話的對象都沒有啊
That's so sad.
真孤單啊
Sir.
部長
I finished the rough bookkeeping of Sales Division.
營業部的概算統計做好了
Nice work.
辛苦了
That was quite a big one.
剛才可真晃呢
Anybody hurt?
大家有沒有受傷？
Are you all right?
-嚇死人了 -沒事吧？
Sir.
部長
I need to leave on time,
這樣會讓我無法準時下班的
so please check it as soon as possible.
請快點確認
All right.
是
Sir.
部長
She acts like this even after an earthquake.
這傢伙就連碰上地震 也是這個樣子
Why is she so particular about leaving on time?
為何這麼堅持準時下班？
Working overtime shows how motivated an employee is.
加班是社員對工作 展現幹勁的方式
You guys still have a lot of work left.
好了各位，今天還有很多工作
Let's clean up and work overtime.
快點整理一下，一起加班吧
Yeah!
是
I've been meaning to ask you this.
我之前也一直想問你
Why can't you work overtime?
你為何堅持不加班？
Overtime is for useless employees who work slow.
加班是工作效率遲緩的 無能社員
It's for them to get extra money.
給薪資灌水的做法
What?
你說什麼？
It doesn't show how motivated an employee is
加班不是幹勁的表現
but how lazy they are at work.
而是怠慢職務的表現
Excuse me.
失陪了
Hey.
等等
Wait.
給我站住
Who do you think we are, Turtleneck?
你把正職員工當成什麼了？ 套頭毛衣女
Bye.
辛苦了
Good, you'll get more overtime money.
各位又多賺一筆加班費了呢
Hey, wait.
你給我等等
Proud employees will have a fall.
高高在上的正職員工 也不保證能安穩一輩子
Companies won't survive without temp workers now.
在這個時代，公司一旦少了 派遣員工就無法正常運作
For example, Haruko Omae here.
例如這位大前春子
"Impossible" and "overtime" are not in her dictionary.
她的辭典中沒有 「不可能」和「加班」
She shuts down all troublesome relationships
排除一切複雜的人際關係
and disappears after three months when her contract ends.
隨著三個月的契約期滿
But why did the super temp worker Haruko Omae
但是仍無人知曉
decide to be a non-permanent employee?
超級派遣員大前春子
That's still a mystery.
為何選擇踏上非正職員工一途
"The Pride of the Temp"
派遣員的品格
Good morning, Marketing Section.
行銷課的各位，早安
Good morning.
早安
This spring, S&amp;F had collaborated with Sils Mario,
我們S&amp;F今年春天
the famous chocolate shop,
將與巧克力名店 Sils Maria合作
and we're going to launch a chocolate gift all over Japan.
在全國販售送禮用的巧克力
Before the launch, to promote and to do research,
因此必須先進行兼具宣傳 與資料收集效用的…
we'll have an Valentine's event.
情人節活動… 別做些奇怪的體操，仔細聽
It's her daily routine.
那是大前小姐的例行運動
It's not 9 yet.
而且也還沒九點
She makes strange noises.
還故意發出一些怪聲…
This is Chief Shoji's project,
這是東海林主任的企劃
but our team will be in charge of it.
將由我們行銷課來負責
Here.
是
You'll organise the event and do research on customers.
請各位幫忙辦活動
Chief!
主任
Don't jump into the conversation.
剛才還在做怪體操 別突然插嘴
This is a large venue, so please get six temps for selling the products.
這麼大的會場，請準備六位 負責販售的臨時派遣員
- I'm-- - I'm Haruko Omae.
-我叫大前… -大前春子
She said it, finally.
終於被我搶先了
She does that every time.
東海林先生，跟她好好相處啦
It's Valentine's Day, after all.
對對，這可是情人節啊
Stop fighting.
別吵了
It doesn't concern her. Right, Turtleneck?
套頭毛衣女跟情人節 完全無緣啦，對吧…
Look, she teleported.
小賢，快看 那傢伙會瞬間移動啊
The meeting isn't over yet.
會議還沒結束吧
You said that it doesn't concern me, so I'm doing something else.
你說跟我完全無緣 所以我先做別的工作了
Is that a problem, Curly Hair?
有什麼問題嗎？自捲主任
"Curly Hair"?
自捲？
Did you hear that?
她剛才說了自捲吧？
- No, she didn't say that. - Yes, she did.
-沒說呀 -明明就有說啊，小賢
She said "Curly Hair".
自捲…她剛才說了自捲吧
- No, she didn't. - Don't just call me Curly Hair.
-沒有啦 -不准你簡稱自然捲
It's Chief Curly Hair.
我是自然捲主任
Never say that to me.
不過也不准你說
They're fighting, after all.
看來又要起爭議了
I think I'll stay in the office.
我看我就負責留守吧
Hi there.
-辛苦了 -受您照顧了
- Here you go. - Thank you.
請多指教
- Here's the name list. - Okay.
大前小姐，名簿在這裡
Quiet, please.
肅靜
Hello, I'm Satonaka from Marketing Section.
初次見面，我是行銷課的里中
Nice to meet you.
請多指教
- Nice to meet you! - He's so cute!
請多指教…真可愛
Quiet, please!
肅靜
Sorry, I gathered them in a hurry, so they're not trained.
真不好意思，實在是…這是 臨時找來的，還訓練不足
No problem.
不會
These two will be organising the event for two days.
那個…這兩位是會在 兩天的活動
Ms Omae and Ms Mori.
大前小姐跟森小姐
Nice to meet you.
請多指教
Wait, I know her.
啊，我知道她
She's so bossy and has a terrible attitude.
她待人很不客氣 讓人感覺很不爽
I don't like to work under her.
我才不想受她指揮呢
You don't?
-你不想嗎？ -合田小姐
She has a terrible attitude.
她態度很差啊
What?
咦？
We'll meet at the venue at 9. Please don't be late.
九點要在現場集合 請各位別遲到了
Okay.
是…
- Here you go. - Oh, wait.
-來 -什麼嘛
You're also a temp from Haken Life?
原來你也是 派遣生活的派遣員啊
Yes, I'm still new, so this is my first big job.
是的，我是新人 第一次擔任這樣的重責大任
But you know about temps retiring at 35?
不過你知道派遣員 35歲就該退休了嗎？
What?
什麼？
The life of a temp ends at the age of 35.
也就是說派遣員的壽命 只有35歲
I'm 36 years old right now.
我現在36歲了
They stopped giving me jobs.
幾乎都接不到工作了
I don't even get consultations.
我連面談都接不到
We only get these urgent jobs.
反正也只有這種臨時的工作
Temps are for running errands, so they only want young, cute ones.
反正派遣員本來就是打雜的 只需要年輕可愛的女生啦
Looking forward to working with you.
總之那兩天請多指教了
See you.
請多指教
Thank you.
請多指教…
"Cafe Cantante"
（歌手咖啡廳）
You're here again?
你又跑來了啊
Should I keep working as a temp?
我該這樣繼續做派遣員嗎？
This is not a therapy room for temps.
這裡可不是派遣員諮商室
Looking at those ladies made me worry.
看到那些人，總覺得有點不安
It's because of me.
「反正我怎樣…」
It's because I'm a temp.
「反正派遣員就是怎樣…」
For temps who say that and make no efforts,
嘴上說著這些話 又不圖努力的派遣員
their life is over.
早就沒救了
That's harsh.
怎麼這樣說啊…
It's easy for you because you have jobs everywhere you go.
當然，像前輩你這樣 工作接不完的人當然無所謂
But for regular temps,
但普通的派遣員當然會很擔心 何時會沒工作啊
Miyuki.
美雪小姐
Listen.
聽我說
The mortality rate for humans is 100 per cent.
人類的死亡率可是百分之百喔
What?
什麼？
Whether you worry or not, someday you'll die.
整天擔心害怕，也一樣會死的
Yeah, you might die tomorrow, so stop worrying.
就是說啊，說不定明天就死了 煩惱也沒用啊
Good for you.
真好
You guys have a Latin way of thinking.
這裡的各位都是拉丁作風啊
Sorry about that.
真不好意思
I'm a girl from Gunma, so I worry a lot.
我可是群馬來的啊
- I'll go dance now. - Okay.
老闆娘，我去跳舞了
I have another thing that I'm worried about.
那個…我還有一個煩惱
Should I hand out chocolates on Valentine's Day?
請問派遣員…是不是要送一下 義理巧克力呢？
Ogasawara, Kon, Asano...
小笠原先生、近先生 跟淺野先生
Director Kirishima and Chief Shoji.
還有桐島部長跟東海林主任
That'll be a lot of money.
可是一大筆開銷啊
You forgot one person.
你是不是忘了某個人了
What?
什麼？
Oh, yeah.
喔…
Yes, Chief Satonaka.
對喔，還有里中主任
Sorry, I forgot.
抱歉，我忘記了
Wait.
怪囉
You're blushing.
臉紅了呢
No, I'm not.
才沒有呢
In any case,
隨便你
nothing is more wasteful than handing out chocolates.
但這世界上沒有比義理巧克力 更無用的東西了
If you have that kind of money,
有這筆錢
save for your retirement.
不如為了退休生活存起來
All right.
請到裡面的房間換衣服
That way.
-好 -請往那邊走
This apron isn't in my size.
這件圍裙尺寸不合啊
I'm sorry.
抱歉
- We only have one size. - Really?
這都是固定尺寸的
Who's the announcer?
-是嗎？ -負責現場叫賣的是哪位？
It's her, Sanae Murase.
是這位村瀨早苗小姐
Read this script.
請你照這份稿唸
I wrote it, so read it with care.
這是我親自寫的稿 要用心好好唸喔
Okay.
是
Ouch.
好痛…
Ken.
小賢
I've never seen anyone who looks so awkward with a heart.
話說還真沒看過 那麼不適合愛心的女人呢
You think so?
會嗎？
She looks cute.
我倒覺得蠻可愛的
Ken.
小賢…
Are your eyes okay?
你眼睛是瞎了啊？
Please.
拜託了
- One bite and it'll captivate you. - For Aida...
合田小姐…你的話…
Last year, I only got one chocolate from my sister.
去年我只收到姐姐給的巧克力
This year, I hope I'll get more chocolates.
今年就算只是義理巧克力也好 真希望能收到
That's so sad.
真可悲呢
You only get one from your wife, right?
近先生你應該也只有 收到太太送的一個吧
Yes, but that one chocolate is a lot more meaningful than yours.
我的巧克力價值可不同
You guys are at such a low level.
你們在聊什麼沒營養的話題啊
Chocolates from family members don't count.
家人送的巧克力根本不算數
- What about you? - Love at first sight.
-那東海林主任你… -我對你一見鍾情
Please accept my feelings.
請收下我的心意吧
What?
什麼？
Thank you.
謝謝…
But I can't do this right now.
但是現在似乎不太適合…
But I've only got two days to work with you,
但我只能跟里中先生你 工作兩天
so I rushed.
一不小心就焦急了起來
I like you.
那個…我喜歡你
Please go out with me.
請和我交往
Well...
那個…
I'm sorry.
抱歉…
I'm flattered...
你的好意我心領了
but please focus on your job now.
但現在請專注在工作上
Don't slack off. Everyone, get to work!
-不好意思 -派遣員別偷懶，快工作
Enough with the drama.
別顧著談戀愛
Read the script now.
快點唸稿
Look at her.
真討厭，自以為是特Ａ級 就跩起來了
She acts like a permanent employee.
還以為自己是正式員工呢
I knew something was missing.
對了，我就覺得少了點什麼
For the announcer, I got this heart hat.
叫賣員啊…
Here.
來
Take this.
對，請戴上吧
There isn't enough chocolate. Get a big pile of them here.
還有這裡…巧克力還不夠 要堆成一座小山啊
Please take a look.
請參考看看
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
If you pile them up here, all the chocolate will melt.
在這邊堆這麼多 巧克力會融化的
It's fine. We just took them out of the refrigerator.
沒問題的 才剛從冰箱拿出來而已
I made them. They're going to melt.
我可是製作者啊
What?
什麼？
Are you an S&amp;F employee?
你是S&amp;F的社員嗎？
No, I'm a temp.
不…我是派遣員
Talking to you won't get me anywhere.
跟兼差的根本沒得談
I'm sorry.
很抱歉…
Well...
那個…
Madam.
這位客人
How can I help you?
怎麼了嗎？
Are you an employee?
你是社員嗎？
All the employees are currently unavailable,
社員目前剛好不在
so I'm here to help you.
由我來代為處理吧
Are you a temp too?
你也是兼差的啊…
Call the person in charge.
請叫負責人過來
Hi there, President Hashidate. Did they do anything to you?
恭迎大駕，橋立社長
Shoji, you're not treating my chocolate right.
東海林先生 這是對巧克力失禮
You can't pile them up and cast them with lights like this.
怎麼能堆得這麼高 直接給燈光照呢
Our chocolate is alive.
我們店的巧克力
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
What are you doing?
你在搞什麼啊
The chocolate is alive.
巧克力可是有生命的啊
I apologise for our ignorant temp staff.
抱歉，我們的派遣員太無知了
This is President Hashidate of Sils Mario.
這位是Sils Maria的橋立社長
We're very sorry.
非常抱歉
- Put them back in the fridge. - Okay.
快點放回冰箱
Quick.
-是 -快點收起來
It was Chief Shoji who told me to pile them up.
明明是東海林主任 要我堆成一座小山的
Why are we the ones apologising?
為何是我們要道歉啊
He blames temps for bad things
壞事都推到派遣員身上
and takes credit for good things.
好事都是本大爺的功勞
That's just how he is.
他就是這種人
You're a temp, after all, even if you're Special A Rank.
就算是特Ａ級 也一樣只是派遣員
Society doesn't trust temp workers.
世人就是不信任派遣員
She was so scary.
真的很可愛呢…
Look.
哦
That looks good.
有便當呢
Thanks.
來
We're in trouble.
不好了
What's going on, Hitotsugi?
-怎麼了？ -一木先生
- What's going on? - Sorry.
-怎麼了嗎？ -非常抱歉
Murase, the announcer, ended her contract and disappeared.
叫賣員村瀨早苗說要解約 不知道跑哪裡去了
What?
啥？
The one who asked Ken out?
叫賣員…是那個跟小賢 告白的女人？
Oh, yeah.
啊
She's heartbroken.
是因為失戀而大受打擊嗎？
Yes, that's exactly right.
對，好像是這樣
She's so heartbroken that she can't stand wearing a heart-shaped hat.
她哭著打電話來說失戀了 不想戴什麼心形頭套
I tried to convince her, but to no avail. I'm sorry.
我已經拼命想說服她了 真的很抱歉
It's not your fault.
這不是您的錯
I was being insensitive.
是我神經太大條了
I told her that in front of everyone.
不該在大家面前那樣說的
Nobody should just quit their job after a heartbreak.
只因為失戀就丟下工作 誰受得了啊
This is why I don't trust temps.
所以派遣員才不值得信任
See?
看吧
Chief Shoji.
東海林主任
Everyone here is against you now.
你剛才已經跟這裡的 所有人為敵了…
Asano.
淺野，你啊
Don't get intimidated.
身為正式員工，怕什麼怕
What should we do about the announcer?
叫賣員該怎麼辦？
I was looking at this.
所以…關於這個
Omae,
大前小姐
according to your job history,
依照你的工作履歷
you were an announcer for election campaigns.
你…
You got three Parliament members elected.
讓三位民意代表當選了吧
Yes. So?
那又如何？
Three Parliament members?
讓三位民意代表當選？
You can do anything then.
真是的，還在搞什麼啊
Why don't you do the announcement?
來，那由你來做不就好了
No, thank you.
我拒絕
Omae.
大前小姐
Don't be so selfish.
不是任性的時候了
You don't like the hat?
你不想戴這個頭套啊
You're saving us.
真是幫我們大忙了
Thank you.
謝謝
Smile. You look too unfriendly for an announcer.
笑一個啊，哪有臉這麼臭的 叫賣員啊
Smile. Smile.
笑一個，微笑、微笑
With feelings.
要帶真感情來唸喔
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
You have to express your feelings.
心意要化為實體才能傳遞出去
February 14th is the best day of the year to take that chance.
2月14日
When you have a bite,
只要放入口中
you'll be captivated by our chocolate.
就會被擄獲
Give Sils Mario's chocolate
只要送上Sils Maria的巧克力
and you will surely captivate your loved one.
-心愛的人也會被您擄獲吧 -小賢
Her voice is cute.
她就只有聲音特別可愛呢
Love comes in different forms.
愛有許多不同形式
Chocolates that you hand out to your co-workers and bosses,
送給上司或同事的義理巧克力
the ones that you give to your friends,
送給朋友的友情巧克力
and the ones you give
或是送給人生多舛者的 島倉千代巧克力
Now,
好了
why don't you try Sils Mario's chocolate?
要不要來點 Sils Maria的巧克力呢？
Limited number available.
數量有限
You need to express your feelings.
心意要化為實體才能傳遞出去
February 14th is the best day of the year to take that chance.
2月14日
When you have a bite, you'll be captivated by our chocolate.
只要放入口中，就會被擄獲
Thank you.
謝謝
Give Sils Mario's chocolate
只要送上Sils Maria的巧克力
and you will surely captivate your loved one.
心愛的人也會被您擄獲吧
Ones that you give to your friends.
送給朋友的友情巧克力…
- Thank you for waiting. - And ones you give to people
-久等了 -請等一下
who've gone through a lot in their lives.
謝謝
This way, please.
請來這裡
- Try Sils Mario's chocolate. - It's a simple questionnaire.
-請幫忙做簡單的問卷 -是關於巧克力的簡略問卷
Limited number only.
數量有限
Please go take a break, Omae.
大前小姐，請先去休息一下吧
No, we need to sell everything before 6:00 for me to leave on time.
不，不在六點前賣完
You need to express your feelings.
心意要化為實體才能傳遞出去
February 14th...
2月14日…
- The fridge is empty now. - Really?
冰箱都空了
We're very sorry, but we're sold out for today.
真的很抱歉
What?
什麼
Thank you.
謝謝各位
We're very sorry.
很抱歉
Please come back tomorrow.
請各位明天再來吧
Everything is sold out now.
真的全都賣完了
Thank you.
謝謝
It's thanks to Omae.
都是託了大前小姐的福
She's so impressive.
果然厲害
Chief.
主任
Can I go home now?
我可以直接回家嗎？
Sure.
好的
Nice work.
辛苦了
I'll go make an additional order at the factory.
小賢，我去跟工廠追加
At this rate, we'll sell out again.
這樣下去明天也會賣完的
That's true.
也對
Should I come too?
我也一起去吧
It's fine, I'm close to their president.
沒問題，我跟那位社長很好的
Come with me, Asano.
淺野，你也來
Sure.
是
- Thanks. - Sure.
-拜託了 -好
- Hey. - Yes?
-那個… -是
The contract said that the job ends at 7.
今天的契約只到七點吧
We're done because the chocolate is sold out?
因為巧克力買光就讓我們先走
We'll get paid until 7, right?
時薪還是該付到七點吧
I'm not sure about that.
不，這個嘛…
You're not sure? What?
-這是什麼意思？ -各位
Don't worry.
不用擔心
We'll pay until 7:00.
時薪我們會付到七點的
Okay, that's good.
那就好
Great.
是啊
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天也拜託各位了
- See you tomorrow.
-是… -拜託了
We can't depend on her at all.
真是不可靠
Who forgot this?
是誰的東西忘了拿？
Excuse me.
失禮了…
What?
什麼？
"Haruko Omae"
（證照）
"Certificate"
（大前春子）
I'm not cut out for this.
光靠我果然不行
I can't lead Aida and everyone.
根本沒辦法率領合田小姐她們
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
That's not true.
沒這回事
You did a great job today, Mori.
你今天
Chief...
主任…
Someday, I want to be a super temp like Haruko.
希望我有一天也能成為 像春子前輩那樣厲害的派遣員
I see.
這樣啊
I know I need to work hard,
雖然我知道自己要更加把勁
but I'm not sure what to work on or how.
但實在不知道該從何努力起
I feel so small, and it makes me even more anxious.
對於渺小的自己
Sometimes I just want to scream.
有時候不安得都想叫出來了
I have to change something.
這樣下去是不行的
Mori.
森
I also feel anxious just as much you do.
關於不安
What?
什麼？
Don't rush.
別著急
Every day, set a small goal.
每天
And we'll do our best.
為此做努力吧
Work hard on what's in front of you now
只要拼命做好眼前的事
and you'll eventually get to a higher level.
總有一天能登上高處的
That's what I believe.
我是這樣想的
Let's believe in ourselves.
相信自己的潛力吧
Yeah, let's do that.
也對
Chief.
主任
Thank you.
謝謝您
See you tomorrow.
辛苦了
Mori?
森
- Yes? - Do you have any plans
-是 -明天晚上
tomorrow night?
你有事嗎？
I want to ask you something.
我有事想跟你商量
Sure.
好的
See you tomorrow.
那麼明天見了
On Valentine's Day?
在情人節找我商量事情
No way, that can't be.
該不會是… 相信自己的潛力啊…
Ouch.
好痛…
Everyone wanted your chocolate.
巧克力大受歡迎
They were sold out by 6:00.
六點就已經全賣光了
We'll probably sell even more tomorrow.
我想明天應該會更熱賣
Can we please add 500 to our order, Hashidate?
所以社長啊…想請您再幫忙 追加500個
Everything is hand made at our store,
我們的巧克力都是親手做的
so we can only make what you ordered before.
光是訂單就應付不過來了
Even my pregnant daughter is helping us out now.
連因為生產而回娘家的女兒 都下來幫忙了
Okay.
哎呀
Thank you.
真是辛苦您了
We can't handle any additional orders.
不可能追加的
Please don't say that.
社長，別這麼說
I'm begging you.
拜託您了
We'll do our best for our spring launch.
為了春天的正式販售 我們也很拼命的
We'll help with anything, even packing in boxes.
我們什麼都能做 要裝盒什麼的都行
You can use this guy here.
請盡量使喚這傢伙
- Please.
拜託了
Let's take the order, Mum.
媽，就幫他們做嘛
What?
什麼？
All right, fine.
真拿你們沒辦法
- Thank you!
非常感謝您
Thank you.
-多謝 -謝謝
What brings you here today?
今天有什麼事？
To deliver this.
我是來送這個的
How could I have done that?
我真是的…
Sorry.
很抱歉
I didn't know whose it was, so I looked inside.
由於不知道是誰的 我有打開看過
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
I was surprised.
嚇了我一跳
Those are all licences?
那些全是證照啊？
Thank you for bringing this.
謝謝你特地送來
- Please excuse me. - Omae.
-失陪了 -大前小姐
Tomorrow,
明天
we want to have a party after the event.
活動結束後，我想跟大家 辦個慶功宴
- Please come. - No.
-請你務必也來參加 -不用了
Please join tomorrow.
明天請你也出席吧
I'll go home on time.
我要準時下班
Everyone in our section
行銷課的大家
wants to be friends with you.
都很想跟你交個朋友
I do too.
當然我也是
Is your company where you go to make friends?
公司是拿來交朋友的地方嗎？
I don't believe in companies,
我不相信公司，所以也不認為 這種地方能交朋友
That's how you feel?
是這樣嗎？
As for me, I like the people on my team.
我很喜歡那些人
Okay. So?
是這樣嗎？那又如何？
Well...
那個…
Omae,
大前小姐你…
you have so many certificates,
擁有那麼多證照
so why are you working as a temp at a company like ours?
為何會在我們這樣的公司 當派遣員呢？
Jobs with the least amount of overtime
因為加班率最低的工作
are usually temp office work.
就是事務相關的派遣員
I want to completely separate work from my personal life.
我想把工作時間跟私人時間 好好分開來
I see.
這樣啊
But tomorrow--
但是只要明天就好…
Please don't make me repeat the same thing.
同樣的話請別讓我一再地說
After my working hours,
我除了工作時間外
I don't want to see any of your faces.
不想看到同事的臉
Excuse me.
那就先這樣了
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
You're quite skilful.
你手很靈巧嘛
If you ever get fired, join our shop.
要是被S&amp;F開除的話 就來我們這裡工作吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Good for you, Asano.
太好了呢，淺野
Here you go.
麻煩了
Here we go.
好耶
Nice work, everyone!
辛苦了
Hey, you.
我說你
We had to work extra hard because of you.
都讓我們做到這程度了
I won't forgive you if these don't sell out.
要是還有賣剩的我可不管
Everyone joined to help out,
工作人員總動員幫忙
and we managed to get everything done.
總算趕上追加的份了
That's great to hear.
這樣啊，太好了
Don't forget to do the research on the new product.
記得也要調查新產品相關情報
Yes, sir. I'll be back.
是
Shoji.
東海林
Here.
-是 -好的
Thank you for the chocolate every year.
謝謝你每年都送我義理巧克力
You're welcome.
不客氣
I expect a gift that's three times pricier.
記得要還我三倍
Understood.
了解了
I'll come check on the event later.
待會我會去看活動狀況的
Okay, I'll give you a discount if you're buying.
要買本命巧克力的話 我會幫你打折的
Okay.
嗯
See you later.
一路順風
You have to express your feelings.
心意要化為實體才能傳遞出去
- February 14th is... - I need to go to the restroom.
-2月14日… -等等，我去廁所，幫我一下
- you'll be... - Try Sils Mario's chocolate!
要不要參考 Sils Maria的巧克力？
- Sils Mario's chocolate... - Only for Valentine's day!
情人節限定，很好吃的
It's only sold at this event. Please come and try.
在別的地方買不到的 參考看看吧
Did something good happen to you?
森，有發生什麼好事嗎？
No, not really.
沒…
Would you like to try Sils Mario's chocolate?
要不要參考一下 Sils Maria巧克力？
Chief Shoji?
東海林主任
Thank you always.
受您照顧了
Please make sure to renew my contract.
下次契約更新也拜託了
Chocolate won't do anything, but I'll take it.
跟巧克力無關，但我收下了
Thanks.
謝謝
Chief Satonaka.
里中主任
Here. I stayed up all night to make this for you.
那個…
Thank you.
謝謝
I was wondering if you're free tonight.
請問…
Sorry, I have a very important plan.
抱歉，今天有些事走不開
I see.
這樣啊
Don't get too deep into this.
談戀愛也要有點分寸喔
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Let's go.
走吧
What's the important plan, chief?
主任，走不開的事是指？
You should join too.
淺野也一起參加吧
What? Asano, too?
淺野也一起嗎？
What's wrong?
森，你怎麼了？
No, nothing.
不，沒事
Mori, can I talk to you?
森
Actually...
其實…
Love comes in different forms.
愛的形式有很多種
Chocolates that you hand out to your co-workers and bosses.
送給上司或同事的義理巧克力
The ones that you give to your friends.
送給朋友的友情巧克力
Now, why don't you try Sils Mario's chocolate?
好了，要不要試試看 Sils Maria巧克力？
Limited number only.
數量有限
Hey. You skipped a line.
喂
"And the ones you give to people
人生多舛者的 島倉千代巧克力呢？
It's stupid, so I cut it.
我覺得太無聊就省略了
It's not stupid. It's the most important.
哪裡無聊啊
Also, the way you read doesn't have any emotions in it.
還有，你的唸法太沒心了
Put some emotions into it.
不只是照唸，要放感情進去啊
- Do it yourself then. - Give it to me.
那你自己唸啊
I'll show you how.
我來示範給你看
You have to express your feelings.
心意不化做實體 是傳達不出去的
February 14th is--
2月14日…住手
Stop it. Stop.
快住手
I can't wear something like that.
主任哪能戴這種東西啊
What about the wig you have on?
戴著那種東西 你不覺得丟臉嗎？
This isn't a wig.
這不是戴上去的
It's my natural hair.
是我的頭髮
You thought I wore a wig?
你以為這是假髮嗎？
People are looking.
客人都在看啊
She thought I wore a wig.
這傢伙太奸詐了
Excuse me.
東海林先生
- Here you go. - Thank you.
請
I'm upset and I'm also hungry.
生氣就覺得肚子餓了呢
Oh wait, someone gave me a chocolate.
對了，我收到巧克力了
I'll eat this chocolate.
來吃點巧克力吧
It's so cute.
真可愛呢
Ken, as a temp,
小賢，這個人啊
don't you think she should hand out chocolates to her co-workers?
就當成派遣的興趣 也給我一個巧克力不就好了
For temps, Valentine's day is when we feel glad
對於派遣員來說 情人節是一年一度
that we're not permanent employees.
「不是正式員工真是太好了」 可以享受這幸福的日子
Why is that, Omae?
大前小姐，為什麼呢？
Unlike female workers who stay at one company forever,
因為不用像一直公司的 女員工一樣
we don't need to hand out chocolates.
到處發義理巧克力
She doesn't get it, Ken.
真是不懂事呢，小賢
Valentine chocolate is like lubricating oil for a company.
義理巧克力是公司的潤滑劑
It's 500 yen well spent.
只要500圓就了事算便宜了
It's like throwing 500 yen in a ditch.
就像把500圓丟到水溝一樣呢
We give back gifts that are three times pricier.
我們在白色情人節 會把巧克力三倍奉還啊
Yeah? Lame handkerchiefs? Those are useless, and...
反正你也只會回送品味很差的 手帕或什麼吧，而且…
What's wrong with that?
送手帕有什麼不對
And what?
而且什麼？
Temps are not guaranteed
派遣員根本無法確認
that they'll be at the company a month later.
在一個月後的白色情人節 能不能繼續待在公司啊
They don't know it's on.
他們沒發現麥克風還開著啊
So what? You're a temp by choice, right?
那又如何？你也是自己喜歡 才在做派遣員的吧
Not everyone choses to be. It's all different for everyone.
不是所有人都是喜歡才做派遣 很多人都有苦衷的
A battle between an employee and a temp. It's so interesting.
派遣員跟正式員工的對抗 很有趣吧
Please turn off the microphone.
近先生，快去把麥克風關掉
Do you have a grudge against us?
你對正式員工有什麼怨恨嗎？
What about you? Do you have a grudge on temps?
你才是 對派遣有什麼怨恨嗎？
Please don't fight today.
兩位先請不要吵了
You never work overtime. You don't get to talk like this.
說來說去，不願意加班的人 就別說這些人
I finish all of my tasks before I go home on time.
我只是在下班時間前 完成社員做不到的事而已
You're right.
就是說啊
You work very fast.
你做工作真的很快
Whose side are you on?
你在幫哪邊啊？
Going home on time? You're so selfish.
說什麼要準時下班 結果只是我行我素而已啊
If I accept to work overtime once,
要是接受一次加班 你們只會越來越依賴派遣員
You're so annoying.
真讓人火大
It's because you didn't sleep.
是因為你昨晚都沒睡啦
I don't need a temp like you.
我不需要你這種派遣員
Shoji.
東海林先生
Okay, I understand.
我明白了
You don't need me.
不需要我是吧
No.
不…
We can't afford to lose you.
你不在我們會很困擾的
You're way more competent than I am.
你比我更能幹
You're so cocky!
你就是這樣太自以為是了
So a temp can't be more competent than an employee?
派遣不能比正式員工 更有能力嗎？
The sad truth is...
很可悲地
temps with a lot of experience are the first ones to be fired.
每次要裁員
"I'm a temp, so nobody will trust me."
反正派遣員就不會被信任
"Working seriously wouldn't get me anywhere."
反正我就算努力也沒用
Only temps who have that kind of attitude will remain at the end.
派遣員們都這樣想真的好嗎？
This actually makes your job much more difficult.
到時候困擾的是你們吧
Shoji.
東海林先生
Please take back what you said.
請你撤回前言吧
All right.
我知道了
But...
但是
why don't you learn skills that make you more like a human?
你應該也多學學待人處事吧
Like being thoughtful, for example.
像是看場面說話之類的
Do you so desperately want chocolate from us?
你就那麼想要義理巧克力嗎？
Of course I do.
當然想要了啊
Shoji.
東海林先生
Without providing any benefits, don't expect anything from us.
對於毫無福利或獎金的派遣 要求這種東西根本錯了
we're not here to cheer up unpopular permanent employees.
我們可不是
Unpopular?
不受歡迎…
You always say something that I can't stand.
你這句話根本是多餘的
I'll get back to work now.
那我要回去工作了
Hey, wait.
我說你啊…
The mic is on.
麥克風沒關…
Temps don't need to butter up to the employees?
派遣員根本不需要 討好正式員工
Chocolate can be expensive.
義理巧克力也很花錢的
Let's not buy it.
放棄了啦
I won't give this.
不送義理巧克力了
I'll return this.
請幫我退貨
- It's stupid. - Please wait.
等等…
What should we do?
小賢，怎麼辦…
I had no idea there were this many temp workers.
居然有這麼多派遣員啊…
Don't just get impressed.
不是敬佩的時候了吧
I'll go advertise at the station.
我去站前找客人來
You're in charge here.
之後就拜託你了
What?
這究竟…
What happened here?
是怎麼回事？
Why is there so much left?
為何還剩這麼多？
We're sincerely sorry.
非常抱歉
A temp worker wouldn't know what she's talking about.
我不想跟兼職的說
My chocolate.
我的巧克力…
Stay strong.
請振作點
My poor chocolate.
真可憐…
Oh, look at that.
真是的
- What did you do? - I'm sorry.
你在做什麼啊
No, it was my fault.
不，是我不好
I'm sorry.
之真的很抱歉
Omae.
大前
If they're upset with us, what will happen to the new product?
惹火了Sils Maria
I'll go and apologise. I'll fix this no matter what.
我去跟對方下跪
I'll be back once it's fixed.
在那之前我不會回來
I'll go too.
我也一起去
You're not an employee. It's not your responsibility.
你不是正式社員
No, I'm coming.
不…我也去
Stay out of this, temp.
派遣員別出鋒頭了
No, I will not stay out of this.
不，我必須這麼做
Stay here.
你就留在公司吧
Haruko?
怪了，春子
It's 6:00.
已經六點了啊
Here.
來
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦了
Where's the Special A Rank?
那個特Ａ級派遣員呢？
She went back to the office.
她回公司了
Okay, tell her this.
那請幫我轉達
Tell her what?
什麼？
Listening to her arguing with the permanent employee
聽她跟正式員工吵
actually cheered us up.
讓我提起精神了
What?
什麼？
I...
我決定
I'll be a serious temp again.
再次好好地做派遣員
Despite how I look,
別看我這樣，可是有簿記一級 跟電腦檢定二級執照的
That's impressive.
這樣啊，真厲害呢
If we keep putting ourselves down, nothing will change.
要是拘泥於派遣員的身分 就只能這樣了
I'll try again too.
我也會再次挑戰
You too. Work hard.
你也是
I will.
好的
Good luck.
加油…
I'll work hard too.
我也要加油
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
We won't let the unsold chocolate go to waste.
我們絕對不會 浪費賣剩的巧克力
I'm sincerely sorry.
真的很抱歉
We're busy, so please go home.
我們正在忙，請回吧
Forget about the new product.
新產品的事就當沒這回事吧
Please, Hashidate.
社長，拜託別這樣
I'm begging you.
求您了
- Are you all right, Ayumi? - Mum, it hurts!
步美，沒事吧
You made her work all night.
都是被你們害得熬夜趕工
The same thing happened for her first child.
她才會比上一胎還早生
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
Are you okay? Can you walk to the car?
你沒事吧？ 可以走到車子那邊嗎？
The baby's coming out.
要生了
Don't push.
別生啊，先別生啊
I can't do this anymore!
媽，我不行了
Ambulance! Call an ambulance!
救護車
Right away.
是
Excuse me.
失禮了
Her water broke.
羊水已經破了
The ambulance will be too late. You'll give birth here.
趕不上救護車了
Give birth here?
-什麼？ -在這裡生？
- Are you... - Just do what I say.
-你… -別管了，照我說的做
- Okay. - Ayumi.
-是… -步美小姐
Can you move?
還動得了嗎？
Bring a mattress here!
請在這裡鋪棉被
A mattress.
棉被…
- Get a mattress. - Okay.
-快去拿棉被 -是
That's impossible.
你也太亂來了吧
Get thread, needles, and alcohol!
你去拿線、剪刀跟酒精
And bath towels!
還有毛巾
- What? - Hurry!
-什麼？ -快點
Okay!
是
- There are people in the back. - Okay.
-裡面有人能幫忙 -是
Ayumi?
步美小姐
It's fine. You'll give birth to a healthy baby.
沒事的，請產下活潑的孩子吧
Wait a minute.
請等一下
Aren't you the temp from S&amp;F?
你是S&amp;F那邊兼差的人吧
I'm Haruko Omae, a midwife.
我是助產士大前春子
"Japan Midwives Association"
（日本助產士會員證 大前春子）
Good heartbeats.
心跳良好
Laying on your back must be hard.
好的，仰躺很累吧
Let's turn to the side.
我們來側躺吧
Here you go.
我拿來了
All men, out.
男人請出去
What?
什麼？
Hurry!
快點
Okay.
是
Good luck.
加油
Ayumi?
步美小姐
Look into your mother's eyes.
好的，請看著媽媽的眼睛吧
Ayumi.
步美
It's all fine.
沒事的
Your baby will come out naturally.
嬰兒會自然出來的
Don't push, okay?
別太用力了
Breathe out.
呼氣…
That's right.
就是這樣
That's right. You're doing great.
就是這樣，做得很好
Ayumi.
步美
It's almost over.
只差一點了
The baby's head is coming out.
嬰兒的頭就要出來了
Relax your body.
請放鬆
Breathe out.
呼…
"Tokyo Fire Department"
（東京消防廳）
It's happening right at this second.
那個…裡面現在
My temp worker...
正在…
Here you go.
好的
You did a great job.
你很努力了
Congratulations.
恭喜
It's a healthy girl.
是個健康的女孩
Thank you.
謝謝
Ms Haruko Omae.
大前春子小姐
The baby's born?
生出來了嗎？
Wow, look at her.
生出來了啊
I'm so relieved.
太好了
Nice work.
辛苦了
Chief Satonaka asked me to tell you something.
里中主任給你的業務聯絡
He wants you to come back to the company before going home.
他要你先別回家
Okay.
是
What am I doing?
我真是的…
I'm back.
我回來了
Chief Satonaka?
里中主任？
Happy birthday!
生日快樂
Tada!
來
Chief?
主任
What's this?
這是怎麼回事？
Omae,
大前小姐
happy birthday.
生日…
Happy birthday!
生日快樂
Sorry.
不好意思
I saw your birthday on your licences.
昨天我看到證照上的 出生年月日了
Your birthday is on Valentine's Day. That's great.
生日在情人節真棒呢
I had no idea you were also a midwife.
沒想到大前小姐 還有助產師的證照呢
You surprised us once again.
又讓人大吃一驚了呢
So what?
那又如何？
I'll ask for you when I have a second kid.
我們家也要生第二胎了 拜託囉
We heard it was a girl.
聽說生下一個健康的女孩啊
The same birthday as you.
跟前輩同一天生呢
She'll probably grow up with strong luck just like you.
肯定也是個運氣很好的女孩啊
Also, earlier
對了，剛才
Shoji called me.
東海林先生打電話來了
We can launch Sils Mario's new product.
Sils Maria的新產品
It doesn't concern me.
跟我無關
In any case, nice work.
總之辛苦你了
It's your first time working overtime, Haruko.
春子前輩第一次加班呢
- Not willingly. - Yes.
我也不願意
Come on, let's make a toast.
快點來乾杯吧
Yeah, let's do that.
-就是說啊 -對啊
Please take a glass.
那請大家拿起杯子吧
Here.
請用吧
All right.
那麼
To Omae's health and future success.
預祝大前小姐的健康
Cheers!
乾杯吧
Please stop!
請別這樣
This is a fire hazard.
要是引發火災
Be careful.
就不好了
This cake is a gift from Mori.
這蛋糕是森送的
I saved money by not buying chocolate.
我用義理巧克力的錢買的
- It's wasteful. - What?
沒用的
Birthday cakes are more wasteful than Valentine's chocolate.
生日蛋糕
Haruko.
前輩…
We get older whether we like it or not.
人放著不管也會變老
And what's up with that hat?
而且你頭上戴的那是怎樣
Sorry.
很抱歉
I didn't know how I can celebrate this.
我沒辦法好好表達
So I wore this.
忍不住就戴上了
Your meddling...
你的多管閒事
is honestly creepy.
老實說真的讓人很不舒服
Do you always consider other people's feelings
你有好好理解對方的心情
when you interact with them?
才來接待對方嗎？
No wonder you're out of Sales Division.
就是這樣才會被調離營業部
I'm sorry if I hurt your feelings.
讓你不開心的話我道歉
You might yell at me again...
或許又要被你罵了
but we all wrote this.
但這是大家一起寫的
You did this during your work hours?
這種東西
It's quite shocking.
真令人傻眼
To me, it's like S&amp;F
就像是把S&amp;F的
is throwing their money into a ditch.
時薪跟薪水
That's all.
以上
"Omae,
大前小姐
I can be sloppy.
今後也請幫助沒用的我
"Kensuke Satonaka"
（里中賢介）
"Haruko,
春子前輩
I'm sorry for always troubling you."
抱歉，總是給你添麻煩
"Miyuki Mori"
（森美雪）
"Ms Omae,
大前小姐
I want to see you smile sometimes."
偶爾也請讓我看看你的笑容吧
"Tsutomu Asano"
（淺野務）
"I respect you."
我很尊敬前輩你
"Kosaku Kon"
（近耕作）
"Turtleneck,
套頭毛衣女
by the way, how old are you?"
話說你到底幾歲了啊？
"Wavy tough guy"
（男子漢）
"Haruko,
春子
you're actually a nice girl, aren't you?"
你其實是個好女孩吧
"Shigeru Ogasawara"
（小笠原繁）
"Happy birthday!"
（生日快樂）
"Happy birthday"
（情人節快樂）
Temps can't even make proposals?
派遣員不能提案嗎？
Right.
對
- Can you protect Miyuki Mori? - I will.
你有辦法保護森美雪嗎？
What are you doing, making a temp look good?
小賢，別在這種時候 還幫派遣員說話啊
You get more energy with a guy you like?
為了喜歡的男人
- Exactly. - You're an idiot.
是